Guide to the Herbert Machiz Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Herbert Machiz Papers,
1956-1969
Machiz, Herbert.
25 items (1 box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079067
Biographical Note
Theatrical director in New York City.
Scope and Content
Letters to Herbert Machiz, including items from well-known actors and authors Truman Capote, Tennessee Williams, Yukio Mishima, Julie Harris, Paul Bowles, and Gian Carlo Menotti.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 1 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Subjects
Capote, Truman, 1924-1984.; Williams, Tennessee, 1911-1983.; Mishima, Yukio, 1925-1970.; Harris, Julie.; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007.; Theater--New York (State)--New York.; Composers.; Authors.; Dramatists.; Actors.; Theatrical producers and directors.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
M-59 202080 Purchase
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  The series contains cataloged correspondence and an obituary for Herbert Machiz from the New York Times.
  - Anderson, Judith To: Herbert Machiz, Santa Barbara, CA, [n.d.], (4 t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bowles, Paul To Herbert Machiz, Bangkok, Thailand, 29 September 1966, (2p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [copy on microfilm]
  - Bowles, Paul To Herbert Machiz, Tangier, Morocco, 24 November 1967, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bowles, Paul To: Herbert Machiz, Tangier, Morocco, 13 July 1968, (2p. a.l.s., (with autograph music score for the wedding party music in In the Summer House and a.n. on the bottom of the score) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [Copy on microfilm]
  - Capote, Truman, Bridgehampton, N.Y. (?), ca. 16 December 1968, (1 photo) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [must be called for]
  - Gordon, Ruth To Herbert Machiz, New York, NY, 15 September 1963, (3p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hampton, Christopher To: Herbert Machiz, London, 17 October 1968, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harris, Julie To Herbert Machiz, [n.p.], 29 May 1967, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Keene, Donald Lawrence To Herbert Machiz, New York, 14 September 1968, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Machiz, Herbert Club Supreme 1st Meeting, [n.p.], 14 October [n.y.], (1p. d.s., (also signed by Bette Davis, Anthony Quinn, and others) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo To Herbert Machiz, [n.p.] & Hamburg, Germany, [n.d.] & 2 May 1969, (2 a.l.s, 1 t.l.s. (fragment, photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Henry To: Herbert Machiz, Pacific Palisades, CA., 18 May 1963, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Henry To: Herbert Machiz, [Pacific Palisades, CA.], 24 May 1963, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Henry To: Herbert Machiz, Pacific Palisades, CA, 26 May 1963, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Henry To: Herbert Machiz, Pacific Palisades, CA., 10 June 1963, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, Tokyo, [3 February 1961], (1p. cablegram) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [(Gift of Albert M. Baer, George V. Cooper, and anon. donor, 1971)]
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, [Tokyo], 18 February 1961, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [ (Gift of Albert M. Baer, George V. Cooper, and anon. donor, 1971)]
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, [Tokyo], 11 May 1961, (1p. a.l.s. ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, [Tokyo], 13 October 1961, (3p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, [Tokyo], 5 February 1962, (4p. a.l.s. ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, [n.p.], 8 June 1967, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mishima, Yukio To: Herbert Machiz, Bangkok, [n.d.] & 13 October 1967, (1p. a.l.s; a.n. (included is a NYT clipping by Donald Keene) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nabokov, Vera (Mrs. Vladimir) To Herbert Machiz, Montreux, Switzerland, 9 June 1969, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nabokov, Vera (Mrs. Vladimir) To: Herbert Machiz, Lugano, Switzerland, 30 June 1969, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Natwick, Mildred To: Herbert Machiz, [New York] (?), 13 April 1967, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rice, Elmer To: Herbert Machiz, Stamford, Connecticut, 27 January 1967, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Straight, Beatrice To: Herbert Machiz, New York, 4 May 1967, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Tennessee To: Herbert Machiz, New York, 15 February 1956, (1p. telegram) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Carl" To: Herbert Machiz., [Los Angeles], 4 November [n.y.], (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Obituary of Herbert Machiz, New York, 28 August 1976, (1p. photocopy ) (Box 1, Folder 3)